Guide to the Communications Workers of America, District 2 Arbitration Cases WAG.218
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, District 2 Arbitration Cases
1951-1991
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America. District 2
WAG.218
72 Linear Feet in 72 boxes.
3 websites in 3 archived websites.
Communications Workers of America, District 2 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Virginia, West Virginia, and Washington DC. The collection mostly contains grievances and arbitration cases.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Historical/Biographical Note
Communications Workers of America, District 2 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Virginia, West Virginia, and Washington DC. The district represents workers in telecommunications, airlines, broadcast and cable television, health care, public service, printing and news media, food service, higher education and law enforcement. The district was ran by Vice President Peter G. Catucci from 1986-2008. In 2011, District 2 merged with District 13 and Edward Mooney was elected Vice President.
Scope and Contents note
The collection mostly contains grievances and arbitration cases with telecommunication companies, including C&P Telephone and AT&T, settled by the district. The collection also includes agreements, as well as the district's website from 2009 onwards.
Conditions Governing Access
Arbitration and grievance files are closed. These files appear in boxes 1-12, 26-30, 38-40, 42-45, 47, 49-55, 57, 58, 60-62, and 64. The rest of the materials are open without restrictions.
Other Finding Aids
A more detailed inventory is available in the repository.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
http://district2.cwa-union.org/ was initially selected by curators and captured through the use of The California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service in 2009 as part of the Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) Web Archive. In 2011, the website redirected to https://district2-13.cwa-union.org/. In 2015, this website was migrated to Archive-It. Archive-It uses web crawling technology to capture websites at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy, from the resulting WARC file, of the website. In 2021, the website redirected to https://cwad2-13.org/ and was added to the web archives. The accession number associated with this URL is 2021.061.
Donated by the Communications Workers of America, District 2, in 1994. The accession number associated with this gift is 1994.022.
Take Down Policy
Archived websites are made accessible for purposes of education and research. NYU Libraries have given attribution to rights holders when possible; however, due to the nature of archival collections, we are not always able to identify this information.
If you hold the rights to materials in our archived websites that are unattributed, please let us know so that we may maintain accurate information about these materials.
If you are a rights holder and are concerned that you have found material on this website for which you have not granted permission (or is not covered by a copyright exception under US copyright laws), you may request the removal of the material from our site by submitting a notice, with the elements described below, to the special.collections@nyu.edu.
Please include the following in your notice: Identification of the material that you believe to be infringing and information sufficient to permit us to locate the material; your contact information, such as an address, telephone number, and email address; a statement that you are the owner, or authorized to act on behalf of the owner, of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed and that you have a good-faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law; a statement that the information in the notification is accurate and made under penalty of perjury; and your physical or electronic signature. Upon receiving a notice that includes the details listed above, we will remove the allegedly infringing material from public view while we assess the issues identified in your notice.
Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z West Virginia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Virginia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z District of Columbia.; Telecommunication |x Employees |x Labor unions |z Maryland.; Communications Workers of America. District 2
- Inventory
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Holck-Murphy (Box 1)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Harris-Young (Box 2)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Barker-Toler (Box 3)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Vaughn-Russels (Box 4)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Buck-Comb (Box 5)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Copeland-Head (Box 6)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Hobar-Robinson (Box 7)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Cundiff-Jolley (Box 8)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Matheny-Hobar (Box 9)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Howerton-Kersey (Box 10)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: Kinney-McGoines (Box 11)
  - Closed Arbitration Cases: McKenly-Parker (Box 12)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won & Transcripts: Local 2001, 2004, 2010, and 2011—Wildcat Strike thru Biscom-Supervisors Retrieving Biscom Terminal Info. (Box 13)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won & Transcripts: Bypass of Special Clerks for Engineering Assistant thru McAllister, Gary (Box 14)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won & Transcripts: McAllister-Shacreaw (Box 15)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won & Transcripts: Smack-Westfield (Box 16)
  - C&P Telephone Telephone Cases Denied: Local 2202-#2377-Recall of AT&T Employees thru Flanagan, Lary F. (Box 17)
  - C&P Telephone Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Cooper-Faber (Box 18)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Local 2011-Reduc. In Pay thru Benson, Margaret (Box 19)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Fluker-Kiper (Box 20)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Fleming-Gwaltney (Box 21)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Harris-Smith, Joseph F. (Box 22)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Smith, William A. –Williams, Norman (Box 23)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Wilson, Bruce – Downing, Mary Lou (Box 24)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Dumahaut, Jerry – DeFriece, Quesenberry (Box 25)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: Foley, Fay – Moore, Kathy (Box 26)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: Nat'l Association of Social Workers thru Storer Cablevision of Richmond (Box 27)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: United Technologies Communications Co. thru Local 2300; Wilson, Gregory (Box 28)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: Delbrugge, Thomas –Evans, Norma (Box 29)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: Local 2336/ M. Fife thru Buck, Brenda; Suspension 3/26/88 (Box 30)
  - C&P Telephone Bargaining Minutes and Memorandum of Agreements: 1954 C&P/CWA Bargaining Minutes thru 1959 C&P Bargaining Minutes (D.C. Area) (Box 31)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won and Transcripts: Lynch, Dennis thru Russo, William A. (Box 32)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Lapanne, Larry – Parkersburg Operator Group (Box 33)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Collins, Marcellus – Cox, Roberta (Box 34)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Brumfield, Charles C. – Cook, Glenn D. (Box 35)
  - C&P Telephone Agreements and Memorandum of Agreements: 1960 Memorandum of Agreement thru 1965 C&P/CWA Wage Reopener (Box 36)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won and Transcripts: Costley, Denise – Hite, Richard (Box 37)
  - Closed Grievances from 1991 and Back—Local 2323 and Local 2300: Local 2300; Lutchman, Zilla thru Destacy, Alice (Box 38)
  - Closed Out Contact Interp. Grievances: Sandra, Alker – LaForce, Teresa (Box 39)
  - Closed Grievances from 1991 and Back: Rhea, Jackie – Matthews, Ernestyne (Box 40)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won and Transcripts: Armstrong, Sandra – Corbett, Carol (Box 41)
  - Closed Grievances for Local 2336: Fisher, Patricia – Local 2336 DCB2-D-077-88 (Box 42)
  - Closed Grievances for Local 2336: Select Job Assignment thru Proctor, Dorothy (Box 43)
  - Closed Out Contact Interp. Grievances: Anderson, Andrew L. – Zaccardi, Barbara L. (Box 44)
  - Closed Out AT&T Grievances: Harley, Veronica – Yankowski, Edward (Box 45)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Seiple, Robert – Wagoner, Diane (Box 46)
  - Closed Grievances for Local 2336: Riddick, Leslie – Turner, Robert (Box 47)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Parson, Sonja L. – Seaton, Elizabeth (Box 48)
  - Arbitration Cases Closed-AT&T and Other: Local 2001; Naire, Tom thru Local 2277; Davis, David (Box 49)
  - Closed Out Contract Interp. Grievances: Lemon, Tammy- Local 2001 thru Zebley, Bob-Local 2001 (Box 50)
  - Closed Out Contract Interp. Grievances: Adams, Bruce-Local 2150 thru Young, Kay (Box 51)
  - Closed Out Contract Interp. Grievances: Local 2300 1989, 1991, 1992 thru Local 2323, Bing (Box 52)
  - Closed Out Contract Interp. Grievances: NASW thru Trelawney & Fries (Box 53)
  - Closed Out AT&T Grievances Local 2252 1990-1992: Ahn, Hee S. thru Wormley, Noel (Box 54)
  - Closed Out Arbitration Cases AT&T and Other: Hardy, Louis thru Williamson, Wayne (Box 55)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Walker, Thomas E. thru Zebley, Robert (Box 56)
  - Closed AT&T Grievances Local 2300, 2323, and 2336: Hebron, Deborah-Local 2300 thru Wheeler, Kevin-Local 2336 (Box 57)
  - Closed Out Arbitration Cases AT&T and Other: Anderson, Amy thru Zimmerman, Nathan (Box 58)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Won and Transcripts: Glassco, Charles thru Lloyd, John (Box 59)
  - Closed Out Arbitration Cases AT&T and Other: Local 2250 (Increase of Work Hours) thru Trammell, Janet G. (Pat) (Box 60)
  - Closed Out Arbitration Cases AT&T and Other: Alvis, Donald thru CWA & NASW (Box 61)
  - Closed Out Arbitration Cases AT&T and Other: UTW (Contracting Out) thru Western Union (Box 62)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Settled: Berger, Virginia thru Collier, Ingeborg (Box 63)
  - Closed Out AT&T Grievances: Bostick, Michael thru Wisman, Mike (Box 64)
  - C&P Telephone Agreements and Wage Reopeners: 1951 General Agreement thru 1953 C&P Memorandum of Agreement (Box 65)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Wirt, Herbert L. thru Woodis, Alexander (Box 66)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Denied: Galimore, Erman thru Owens, James D. (Box 67)
  - Faubert, M. thru Rodriguez, Mary (Box 68)
  - C&P Telephone Cases Lost and Transcripts: Local 2001 Travel Allowances, Etc. thru Branham, Edward (Box 69)
  - Unit Clarification of Confidential Clerks thru Vaught, John (Box 70)
  - AT&T Local 2001-Bowe, Amy thru Local 2201-Winborne, Sandra (Box 71)
  - AT&T Local 2001-Beltran, Rosa thru Yost, Mike (Box 72)
- Archived Websites, March 2009-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites.
  Scope and Content Note
  District 2-13 is responsible for servicing all CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government. Capture of the website began in 2009 at http://district2.cwa-union.org/. News listings on the website date back to 2004, focusing on bargaining, strike votes, voice over internet protocol (VOIP), cable, Verizon, AT&T, T-Mobile, conferences, workplace injuries, and political action campaigns. In late 2010, the website redesigned. It contains district and national CWA news, photographs, bargaining with Mobility and AT&T, CWA-COPE (the political action committee) information, and event listings. At the 2011 CWA convention, Districts 2 and 13 merged and the website reflects that change. From 2011-2016, the website spotlighted action campaigns related to the 2011 Verizon strike, petition, and picket line; the sale and merger of T-Mobile USA to AT&T; the Piedmont Agents local union; Call Center Worker and Consumer Protection Bill; opposition to the Trans-Pacific Partnership; scholarships, and bargaining with SuperMedia LLC, Verizon, AT&T, USAir, LifePath, Inc., Consolidated Communications, Inc., American Red Cross, Frontier Communications, Atlantic Broadband, Windstream, Duquesne Club, Comcast, DE State 9-1-1 and Civilian Employees, Verizon Select Services, United States Infrastructure, AT&T Mobility, Verizon TeleProducts, INOVA, Delaware State 922 and Civilian Employees, the Greenbrier CSX Hotels, United Planning Organization, Share Group, PIW, American Airlines, ITS, Catholic Charities of Washington, DC, and Dex Media. In 2017, the layout of the website was changed, with additional bargaining updates from Altice, MX1, Nokia, DirecTV, and Thryv. The website also focused on Pennsylvania get out the vote and endorsements. In 2020, the website focused on resources for membership on the COVID-19 pandemic and anti-racism work.
  In 2021, the Communications Workers of America, District 2-13 redesigned their website and started using an new URL. CWA District 2-13 provides services for CWA locals in Pennsylvania, Maryland, Delaware, Virginia, West Virginia, and the District of Columbia. The websites contains union political endorsements, bargaining reports at their workplaces (Altice, American Airlines, American Red Cross, AT&T, AT&T Mobility, Atlantic Broadband, AVAYA, Community College of Baltimore, CCI, Century Link, Comcast, Delaware State Employees, Duquesne Club, Frontier, ITS, LifePath, Nokia, Piedmont Airlines, PIW, Printing, Publishing, and Media Workers, Thryv, Verizon and Windstream), scholarships, broadband access, and other news from the union.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued monthly.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of cwad2-13.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.